Let's talk about the singly linked list search, so insertion into a singly linked list have three cases
like inserting notes or inserting elements we have to insert.
We have three options inserting a new note before to the head at the beginning and setting in, you
know, after the tail if there's at the end of the list and inserting a new note at the middle of the
list, which is at random location not to insert an element in linked list at some position be assumed
that after insertion the element the position of the of this new node is B.
OK.
We will see this example on this note.
And they're following videos.
So this is.
Our link, at least 1866 one one nine is pointing to now, and we start at, we have three cases at
the beginning in blue, in the middle, in green and at the end in red.
OK, so let's start configuring every thing, every insertion case along.
So inserting a note at the beginning.
We will start by struct node.
And the reference equal equal to no.
So they had reference equal to none.
We call the method void at first.
And then it took an invaluable as a perimeter.
I will call at first ninety nine, ninety nine, so I am calling this method and I need to add the first
element.
Nine nine, I will create a variable in the memory and stored it.
989 So at the left, we are making a general function and to the right, I am showing you the execution
of this method.
By passing the variable 99 so struct known, I will create a new normal malloc memory allocation and
the size of struct note.
So this is the note and you know, I'm creating a new know and the new node.
The data of the new node is equal to the value.
OK.
The van that we have passed, so go to the Val valuable and get the data and store it inside the data
of then, you know, now that reference the new node next equal to had.
So, yeah, give the new not a reference to the hat, but the head is equal to null.
So because of this?
Of this had equal to new not no.
This is the insertion, the note at the beginning.
So we don't have any nods.
We are creating the first note.
So this would result in inserting a note at the beginning and adding this of as a first note.
Now let's consider, and certainly not at the beginning.
But we have variables now.
I need the Senate to create the same thing at first.
We have and Van and I passed now five.
I have the same linked list that contains ninety nine and the point and I need to insert at the beginning
of this link at least that not that contains a value of twenty five.
It's the same way you know I will create in you not put that data equal to value.
I am getting the value that I have best, which is at first twenty five.
So the perimeter 25 have been being reserved in the memory and inside the variable called fan.
And this val, I am putting its value inside that data section of the not.
OK.
And the reference new node next equal to had I am referencing or referencing that, then you know that
I have created.
So I am referencing that a reference of the new node that I have created that address 2024 to hat.
I am telling it, Hey, go and put that reference to your next would be the head, which is equal to
you.
Not so.
I am putting here the hat and back to the first note that I have created.
So we have created a linked list that contains 989 as the first element.
And if I need to add more nodes at the end to this link, at least I should follow these steps in order
to tell that they have now the first element.
The beginning of this linked list would be equal to the node that contains 25.
OK.
This is the best case scenario is all of one, and the worst case scenario is of one because we are
inserting an element, add the first note.
We are just adding the position one.
We are just adding new nodes and the first position, it's very simple.
This has the advantages of linkage.
Now let's see how to do that and how to insert node at the beginning and job.
We will create a public void method called push.
It took inside a perimeter new data type and and we start by node.
And, you know, equal and you know, I'm creating it by using the constructor and getting the new data
and make next of new node, as had I'm referencing the new not the next equal to hat.
Now let's move to the hat to the point to the new nought point a new node had equal to no, no.
I'm telling that to have now is equal to the newly created no.
The best case scenario is oh, one worst case scenarios.